

# Kalaipriya Kannan

L&D SME | Professional Scrum Master (PSM1)



+91- 9840511730



kalaipriya.kannan@gmail.com

Certified Scrum Master and Seasoned Business Analyst offering 10 years of industry experience in L&D space. Expert on business and systems requirements, with excellent organizational and project management skills. Diligent and flexible with strong communication and organizational skills. Worked on various portfolio such as Life Sciences, Healthcare, and L&D Data Reporting. Strong experience in Business Analysis and Data Analysis, proficient in SQL, Tableau.



#### Skills

S.	Skills	
•	Business Need Analysis	<b>Excellent</b>
•	Project & Team Management	Very Good
•	Requirement Analysis	<b>Excellent</b>
•	Data Analysis & Reporting	Very Good
•	Business Consulting & Advisory	<b>Excellent</b>
•	Strategic planning	••••



## **Work History**

Agile Methodologies

2021-04 - Current

# Sr. L&D Co-ordinator

Carelon Global Solutions, Bangalore

• Part of AIO team, collaborating with Learning Infrastructure responsible for co-ordination and support of the organization's learning and operations.

Very Good

Good

- Proficient in Workday system functionalities, published and managed the
  revisions of the learning events from self-paced to blended learnings as
  directed by business leads and Enterprise Learning operations standards.
- Assisted with the release testing of learning system upgrades, coordinating
  with business leads, contributing to the enhancement of employee training
  programs and organizational development initiatives.

- Managed and update the LMS with new training modules, and EIBs,
   Campaigns to bulk enroll the compliance training programs.
- Developed and managing various reports in SNOW for AIO monthly metrics provides insights on the trends and effectiveness of training initiatives through feedback and performance metrics.
- Maintained training records and tracked employee progress through the LMS, comply requests from legal and compliance by providing custom historic training records.
- Reporting monthly data analysis findings to leadership to use in making organizational L&D decisions
- Analyzed key aspects of business to evaluate factors driving results and summarized into presentations.
- Generated ad-hoc reports to evaluate specific business requirements.
- Supported leadership team with reporting, analysis, and business presentations to inform divisional strategies.

#### Business Lead & Subject Matter Expert of L&D

Deloitte USI, Hyderabad

- With strong experience in areas of change and release management, defect analysis, system configuration, stakeholder communication and providing training related to new learning solutions
- Managed team of 6 and acted as escalation point of contact for various learning leads across EMEA and APAC region, directly interacted with vendor for any change requests or enhancement requests basis the need
- Collaborated with Project Owners, Project Managers to provide functional release per sprint cycle
- Assisted management with backlog refinement sessions
- Identified and implemented operational improvements, enhancements, customizations and rolling out learning solutions that arise from the need analysis, communications & project management
- Facilitated various user groups meeting with learning leaders across member firms in different geographical regions for best practices and gaining consensus visioning to business growth

#### Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai

- Worked on L&D requirements and delivered to meet client needs for functionality and organization development.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality prior to release.
- Developed need based training modules for developing multi skilled work force and mentored new team members to come up learning curve
- Managed the team of 12 for a large pharmaceutical client in the UK with focus on excelling business targets & service delivery metrics

2017-05 - 2021-03

2014-07 - 2017-04

- Monitored and evaluated metrics, prepared reports on standards & performance target
- Ensured quality services are provided and document functionalities are maintained



## **Education**

2010-08 - 2014-04

## **B.Tech: Information Technology**

Vel Tech Institutions - Chennai



# **Certifications**

Professional Scrum Master (PSM1)

Google Project Management Professional

IBM Certified Big Data and Data Science Foundations

Scrum Concepts & Product Owner

Agile Principles & Methodologies



#### **Technical Skills**

SQL

Tableau

Advanced Excel

HTML & Postman



## **Tools Worked**

JIRA

ServiceNow

Salesforce

Remedy

MS SQL Server

Oracle DB



### **LMS Worked**

SuccessFactors

Saba

Plateau

Corner Stone On Demand (CSOD)

Moodle

Oracle

Workday